<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Messages on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/tags/messages/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Messages on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 bcdata</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/2017/tags/messages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting and improving timeliness and personalization of Mobile Engagement messages</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile Engagement messaging is a relatively new domain for marketers.  It is the responsibility of technology companies to ensure that this new way of interacting with their customers is not abused.  At Mobify, we aim to do this by looking at data, to suggest best practices for Engaging with customers to reduce spam, and improve their experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobify collects millions of data points each month and currently delivers a full mobile experience to its clients. With your data modelling expertise, our goal is to personalize shoppers’ mobile experiences to reduce the noise and friction of their mobile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical challenge is to develop predictive models that measure the timeliness and relevance of the mobile messages. Such predictive models can provide recommendations on how best to engage with shoppers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who - Personalize to the different type of shoppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When - When would be best to engage with shoppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What - What content engages with shoppers the most.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available data will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anonymized mobile behaviour data from different brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anonymized Push message content for those customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather data for particular locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
