<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bcdata on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in bcdata on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 bcdata</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop begins</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/talk/start-of-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/talk/start-of-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The workshop begins on August 14. Check back soon for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration deadline</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The deadline for registration for the workshop is 15 July 2017. To
register for the workshop and the pre-workshop, please visit the link above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting and improving timeliness and personalization of Mobile Engagement messages</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile Engagement messaging is a relatively new domain for marketers.  It is the responsibility of technology companies to ensure that this new way of interacting with their customers is not abused.  At Mobify, we aim to do this by looking at data, to suggest best practices for Engaging with customers to reduce spam, and improve their experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobify collects millions of data points each month and currently delivers a full mobile experience to its clients. With your data modelling expertise, our goal is to personalize shoppers’ mobile experiences to reduce the noise and friction of their mobile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical challenge is to develop predictive models that measure the timeliness and relevance of the mobile messages. Such predictive models can provide recommendations on how best to engage with shoppers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who - Personalize to the different type of shoppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When - When would be best to engage with shoppers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What - What content engages with shoppers the most.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available data will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anonymized mobile behaviour data from different brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anonymized Push message content for those customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather data for particular locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Hop: Real-Time Agricultural Sensing</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with hop farmers around the province to develop the
world’s first beer terroir. Terroir is a term used in the wine
industry that refers to the unique flavours and aromas of grapes from
different regions. It’s what people are talking about when comparing a
wine from BC with a similar one from France. We want to work with you
to develop terroir for beer. Instead of using grapes we are focusing
on hops, one of the main ingredients in beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discovering hop terroir is important because hops from all over are
sent to processing facilities to be dried, bundled and sold
together. That means that all the tasty regional differences of each
hop variety are washed out by the time they get to the brewer. Imagine
how boring it would be if you could only order “IPA” or “stout” and
not choose from the thousands of beers produced by different
breweries. That’s what it’s like for hops, with brewers choosing only
“centennial” or “cascade” without being able to pick from different
regions with their own unique flavours. Let’s change this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have developed a soil sensor system that measures temperature and
moisture for both soil and air at different depths and heights,
respectively. Each sensor has one base station with several nodes. We
will collect data from many nodes, across several sensors within a
farm at 5-minute intervals. This will give us a baseline for assessing
growing conditions. We will know, at any given time, the temperature
and moisture content of the air and soil throughout a farm. We will
use these data in conjunction with data on farm management practices,
soil chemistry, and soil microbial genetics to create a set of
dependent variables for a predictive model of the environmental and
management (farming) influences on hop yield and quality. Our
dependent variables will be the weight of harvested hops per
hectare/plant, quality of hops (measured by chemical analysis), and
flavour (measured by brewing several beers using the exact same recipe
and hop variety but from different regions and getting people to drink
them and report back en-masse).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to be able to help farmers produce better hops so that
breweries can make better beers, but we don’t want to have to build
more sensors than is necessary to measure growing conditions on a
farm. This is where we need your help. We are looking to develop an
algorithm that will predict moisture and temperature between senor
nodes. To do this effectively we will provide some additional
data. This will include an elevation map of the farm and information
on soil type and characteristics (e.g. water retention capacity and
compaction)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to predict farm conditions with fewer sensors will help
this technology become more affordable to small-scale producers
allowing more growers to make better and more unique hops so we can
all enjoy great beer. Real-time environmental monitoring of farms will
also help farmers of all crop types have access to a technology that
will allow them to better understand their land and adapt their
management practices in real-time (e.g. changing or automating
irrigation and fertilizer schedules as needed, when needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to the opportunity to work with you on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/registration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Registration is now open! Please complete
&lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/forms/dowiyIBurStIvvEq1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Google form&lt;/a&gt; to register for the
2017 bcdata workshop in data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 bcdata Data Science Workshop</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/workshop-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/workshop-description/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check back soon for full schedule and details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IAM Short Course</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/prequel-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/prequel-description/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-short-course-in-linear-algebra-and-software-tools&#34;&gt;A short course in linear algebra and software tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be an optional short course before the main workshop, covering some
linear algebra theory combined with an introduction to open source software
tools for mathematical computing. This short course will run August 9-11 and
will involve lectures on the theory, combined with computational
examples. Notes will be posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-1-wednesday-august-9&#34;&gt;Day 1: Wednesday August 9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;linear-algebra&#34;&gt;Linear algebra:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linear systems, condition number, sparse direct techniques,
conjugate gradient (Krylov subspace) methods and preconditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt; shell, version control with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jupyter.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; notebooks, and programming in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-2-thursday-august-10&#34;&gt;Day 2: Thursday August 10&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;linear-algebra-1&#34;&gt;Linear algebra:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Least squares (regression), vector Newton’s method, nonlinear optimization
(Newton’s method, gradient descent)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;software-1&#34;&gt;Software:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientific computing in Python: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.numpy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NumPy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scipy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SciPy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://matplotlib.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandas.pydata.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;day-3-friday-august-11&#34;&gt;Day 3, Friday August 11&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;linear-algebra-2&#34;&gt;Linear Algebra:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change of basis (FFT), eigen-analysis, singular value decomposition (principle
component analysis)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;software-2&#34;&gt;Software:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerical computing with NumPy and basic machine learning with &lt;a href=&#34;http://scikit-learn.org/stable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A risk-based platform for accident prevention</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BC Safety Authority’s accident prevention strategy follows a risk
based platform, called “bow tie” for ongoing management and prevention
of major incidents. The bow tie method draws on the direct experience
of safety management team and the data collected from various safety
oversight programs in order to identify hazards and to properly
incorporate critical controls into management systems. In addition, it
raises awareness and improves understanding and risk knowledge of the
potential major incidents and the reliance on critical controls that
prevent those accidents from occurring. Opportunities exist for
greater connectivity among various databases to maximize the risk
knowledge, especially the pre incident data based on inspections and
post incident data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
