<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 bcdata</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/2017/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating enhancer-promoter gene expression using ConvNets</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different cell types in humans possess approximately the same genome despite
having dramatically different functions. Gene regulation is the complex process
by which cells selectively synthesize different proteins encoded in their
genome. [1] A fundamental understanding of how genes are regulated can lead
towards effective treatments for cancers and developmental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enhancers are distal regulatory elements that, in conjunction with a promoter,
recruit the proteins required to drive transcription of a gene. While the
~20,000 genes in the human genome are known, we have not identified all of the
enhancers linked to each gene. The goal of this project is to leverage Altius’s
data on the genome-wide regulatory landscape [2] to match candidate enhancers
with promoters (and, thus, genes) and identify synergistic protein binding
motifs that can reveal key players in enhancer-promoter gene
expression. Convolutional neural networks (ConvNets) [3] are a natural machine
learning algorithm to approach such questions, as they automatically discover
relevant protein binding motifs in DNA sequences from training data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenges include building an interpretable and explainable ConvNet to extract biological insights from our genome-wide regulatory landscape data sets;
and mapping DNA sequences to a vector space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Alberts B, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 4th ed. (2002)&lt;br /&gt;
[2] Thurman RE, Rynes E, Humbert R, Vierstra J, Maurano MT, Haugen E, Sheffield NC, Stergachis AB, Wang H, Vernot B, Garg K. The accessible chromatin landscape of the human genome. Nature. 2012 Sep 6;489(7414):75.&lt;br /&gt;
[3] LeCun Y, Bengio Y, Hinton G. Deep learning. Nature. 2015 May 28;521(7553):436-44.&lt;br /&gt;
[4] Zabidi MA, Stark A. Regulatory enhancer–core-promoter communication via transcription factors and cofactors. Trends in Genetics. 2016 Dec 31;32(12):801-14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-altius&#34;&gt;About Altius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.altius.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Altius Institute for Biomedical Sciences&lt;/a&gt; is an
independent, not-for-profit research institute based in Seattle,
Washington. Altius aims to unlock the potential of the living genome to open
new frontiers for basic science, technology development, and translational
medicine. Altius is developing transformative technologies to understand how a
cell’s genome controls its function in health and disease, and to translate
this understanding effectively into clinical settings in the discovery of new
medicines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Hop: Real-Time Agricultural Sensing</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with hop farmers around the province to develop the
world’s first beer terroir. Terroir is a term used in the wine
industry that refers to the unique flavours and aromas of grapes from
different regions. It’s what people are talking about when comparing a
wine from BC with a similar one from France. We want to work with you
to develop terroir for beer. Instead of using grapes we are focusing
on hops, one of the main ingredients in beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discovering hop terroir is important because hops from all over are
sent to processing facilities to be dried, bundled and sold
together. That means that all the tasty regional differences of each
hop variety are washed out by the time they get to the brewer. Imagine
how boring it would be if you could only order “IPA” or “stout” and
not choose from the thousands of beers produced by different
breweries. That’s what it’s like for hops, with brewers choosing only
“centennial” or “cascade” without being able to pick from different
regions with their own unique flavours. Let’s change this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have developed a soil sensor system that measures temperature and
moisture for both soil and air at different depths and heights,
respectively. Each sensor has one base station with several nodes. We
will collect data from many nodes, across several sensors within a
farm at 5-minute intervals. This will give us a baseline for assessing
growing conditions. We will know, at any given time, the temperature
and moisture content of the air and soil throughout a farm. We will
use these data in conjunction with data on farm management practices,
soil chemistry, and soil microbial genetics to create a set of
dependent variables for a predictive model of the environmental and
management (farming) influences on hop yield and quality. Our
dependent variables will be the weight of harvested hops per
hectare/plant, quality of hops (measured by chemical analysis), and
flavour (measured by brewing several beers using the exact same recipe
and hop variety but from different regions and getting people to drink
them and report back en-masse).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to be able to help farmers produce better hops so that
breweries can make better beers, but we don’t want to have to build
more sensors than is necessary to measure growing conditions on a
farm. This is where we need your help. We are looking to develop an
algorithm that will predict moisture and temperature between senor
nodes. To do this effectively we will provide some additional
data. This will include an elevation map of the farm and information
on soil type and characteristics (e.g. water retention capacity and
compaction)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to predict farm conditions with fewer sensors will help
this technology become more affordable to small-scale producers
allowing more growers to make better and more unique hops so we can
all enjoy great beer. Real-time environmental monitoring of farms will
also help farmers of all crop types have access to a technology that
will allow them to better understand their land and adapt their
management practices in real-time (e.g. changing or automating
irrigation and fertilizer schedules as needed, when needed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to the opportunity to work with you on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A risk-based platform for accident prevention</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BC Safety Authority’s accident prevention strategy follows a risk
based platform, called “bow tie” for ongoing management and prevention
of major incidents. The bow tie method draws on the direct experience
of safety management team and the data collected from various safety
oversight programs in order to identify hazards and to properly
incorporate critical controls into management systems. In addition, it
raises awareness and improves understanding and risk knowledge of the
potential major incidents and the reliance on critical controls that
prevent those accidents from occurring. Opportunities exist for
greater connectivity among various databases to maximize the risk
knowledge, especially the pre incident data based on inspections and
post incident data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven modeling of video compression</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite our hand in their design, and hence their seemingly deterministic
operation, electronic systems grow ever more complex and are often most simply
characterized through measurement-driven modeling. This workshop presents
measurements of the rate at which bits are produced as output of a compression
algorithm for a digital video camera. The data are produced by presenting the
camera with a variety of test scenes, and operating it over a variety of
settings. The data presented here can both simulate the camera&amp;rsquo;s bit rate as a
function of operating conditions for design purposes, as well as provide some
insight into how the camera&amp;rsquo;s compression algorithm operates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several other goals will be presented, and participants will be free to
investigate a variety of possible directions with the data.  Perhaps most
importantly, complete details of how the data are generated &amp;mdash; namely the
internal workings of the camera&amp;rsquo;s algorithm &amp;mdash; are not available.  Despite this
fact, we believe that systems as elaborate as those that can control the
camera&amp;rsquo;s bit rate under changing conditions can be achieved with good modeling
practice on these available data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
